# Shay Nezaki

Vancouver, BC, Canada | (+1) 778-980-9578 | s.nezaki@outlook.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

### **SUMMARY**

I love to transform numbers into strategy. With over 3 years of experience collecting, cleaning, analyzing, and visualizing data in the financial and educational industries, I have a track record of delivering meaningful insights and driving efficiencies. I'm now seeking a role to step up my career in business intelligence and data analytics.

Skills: SQL, R, Microsoft Access, Excel, Google Sheets, BigQuery, Tableau

Languages: English, Japanese

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Marketing Assistant** 

March 2023 - Present

# VanWest College - Vancouver, British Columbia

- Improved the Google Sheet for student information by adding or changing formulas based on team requests, which decreased the time for data entry by 20% while increasing the accuracy of data
- Verified completeness and accuracy of 500+ student applications per year, ensuring compliance with school policies and regulatory requirements
- Liaised between education agents, the admission team, and other relevant departments to provide timely and accurate information for efficient collaboration; responding to inquiries within 24 hours and keeping agents informed of commission rates and promotions

# Program Coordinator / Program Assistant VanWest College – Vancouver, British Columbia

May 2022 - March 2023

- Developed, maintained, and adapted Vocational College Program course schedules to respond to the changing numbers and needs of the college; provided timely and effective solutions in coordination with the Academic Director
- Maintained discretion regarding academic information, current privacy laws, and professional practices between instructors, students, and advisors, as well as other departments in the college
- Coordinated with the Academic Director to communicate academic policies to 1000+ students and responded to policy change inquiries as needed

#### **Research Assistant**

**September 2021 - May 2022** 

# Langara College - Vancouver, British Columbia

Research project: Immigration Education and Employment Pathways for International Students in BC

- Transcribed 20+ interviews with international students about their experiences in Canada to understand their challenges and struggles
- Carried out research into TikTok and YouTube videos posted by international students such as categorizing videos and compiling data on the locations and number of views

# Shay Nezaki

Vancouver, BC, Canada | (+1) 778-980-9578 | s.nezaki@outlook.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

# Marketing Coordinator

October 2017 - April 2019

# Rakuten Bank - Tokyo, Japan

- Launched new promotions after analyzing the timing and value of personal loans using Microsoft Access, which led to a 15% increase in customer borrowing
- Analyzed the number of outbound calls in which call center agents succeeded in providing loans to customers and increased the number of successful calls by 20% compared to before the data was organized using Microsoft Excel and Access
- Re-engaged customers by sending direct mail to those who could not be reached by email
  or phone, which led to a 5% year-on-year increase in the number of customers who took
  out loans

# Customer Service Supervisor

**June 2016 - September 2017** 

# Rakuten Bank - Tokyo, Japan

- Mentored 40 call center agents, managed escalations, took over serious complaints, and held monthly meetings to give feedback, which resulted in less than 10% of the turnover rate in a year
- Handled approximately 40 phone calls from customers per day and offered solutions, which kept the abandon rate less than 4%

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

**Immigrant Advisory Table Member** 

March 2022 - August 2023

# Vancouver Local Immigration Partnership - Vancouver, British Columbia

 Supported VLIP research initiatives and provided information and expertise on local immigration trends and needs of the community

# **Human Resources Assistant**

July 2021 - August 2022

#### Canadian Red Cross - Ottawa, Ontario

- Reviewed resumes and screened applicants who applied to emergency responder roles
- Collaborated with other HR assistants and the HR coordinator to track applicants and achieve department KPIs, such as response time to application using Taleo and Smartsheet

#### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

Google Data Analytics Professional CertificateIssued in December 2023BrainStation Data Analytics CertificateIssued in September 2021

**Business Administration, Post-Degree Diploma** 

May 2020 - April 2022

Langara College, Vancouver, British Columbia

**Bachelor of Laws, Administrative Law** 

April 2012 - March 2016

Waseda University, Tokyo, Japan